CONTACT

וֹח New York, NY



http://jakepeyser.com



jakepeyser@gmail.com



(203) 803-3188



FOLLOW

github.com/jakepeyser



linkedin.com/in/jakepeyser \mathfrak{M}



INTRODUCTION

I am a software engineer with a passion for product development and user experience. My work in web development, product management, and consulting has molded me into a full stack web developer capable of delivering all aspects of a web application from inception to production.

SKILLS

Front End: JavaScript (ES6), React, Redux, Vue, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Sass, Stylus

Back End: Node, Express, Sequelize, Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy

Tools: Git, Travis CI, Webpack, Heroku, Bluemix, Sketch, Illustrator, Keynote

Data: PostgreSQL, Elasticsearch, Cloudant, Mongo

EXPERIENCE

Fyre Media - New York, NY

2017 - Present

- Software Engineer
- Developing bookings platform to connect buyers with the world's best talent
- Building real-time search engine for our global talent database

IBM - Austin, TX

2015-2016

- Developer Advocate
- Led agile team of peers building enterprise showcase demos
- Developed open source sample apps and tools to enable Bluemix developers
- Evangelized product in developer community to help grow 500% to >1M users
- Collected user feedback used to conduct inbound product management

IBM - Austin, TX 2013-2015

Business Process Management Consultant

- Modeled and implemented business processes using BPMN 2.0 and agile
- Co-architected industry-leading bank's new due diligence system of record
- Designed and implemented vital integration solution for due diligence process to meet OCC compliance deadline and avoid significant fine

EDUCATION

University of Michigan

B.S.E. Computer Science

- Graduated 2013 (cum laude)
- Math and Entrepeneurship Minor
- 3x Dean's List & 2x Honors

Fullstack Academy of Code

- Focus in front end development
- Studied the Node, Express, React, and PostgreSQL stack

INTERESTS



Fitness



Traveling



Cooking Mindfulness







Reading

2015

PROJECTS

Steps

Designer & Developer

Physical therapy exercise tracking system for keeping patients informed and engaged while providing therapists with relevant data and key insights into their clients' recovery

github.com/jakepeyser/steps



steps-app.herokuapp.com

2016 Parachute Teachers

Back End Developer

Reimagined substitute teacher management network connecting schools looking for qualified substitutes and community members wanting share their knowledge with students.

parachuteteachers.com

2016 Real-time Tone Front End Developer

Transcribe spoken or recorded audio in real time and track the emotional, language, and social tone of the transcribed text via a configurable, streaming graph.





2016 Capital Weather Full Stack Developer

Discover current, forecasted, and historical weather data at

any location around the world by interacting with a dynamic mapping interface provided by Esri.



github.com/IBM-Bluemix/ capital-weather

